<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GUANGHUIZ</title>
    <description>Know all about me from here.</description>
    <link>http://www.guanghuiz.com/en/en/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.guanghuiz.com/en/en/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 20:51:24 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 20:51:24 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Data Exploration with R -  Quality of Red Wine</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The dataset contains 1600 kinds of red wines. Each wine was rated by profesionalists with a quality score ranging from 0 to 10. And the chemical compositions of each red wine was measured. Use R to explore the dataset of Red Wine with the objective to find the most relevant metrics of red wine to its quality score.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click to download &lt;a href=&quot;/en/data/wineQualityReds.csv&quot;&gt;red wine dataset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Click to view the &lt;a href=&quot;/en/data-science/data-exploration-project-1.html&quot;&gt;data exploration project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.guanghuiz.com/en/en/data-science/2016/05/28/data-exploration-with-r-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.guanghuiz.com/en/en/data-science/2016/05/28/data-exploration-with-r-1/</guid>
        
        <category>data</category>
        
        <category>science,</category>
        
        <category>data</category>
        
        <category>explore</category>
        
        
        <category>data-science</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Listen and Listen Well</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I watched a very informative and educative video named &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/H6n3iNh4XLI&quot;&gt;“How to be a better conversationalist”&lt;/a&gt;. In the video, the speaker gave a dozes of advice on how to make a better conversation when talking with people, among which the last one is to listen. This is not the first time when I heard people stressed the importance of listening. But none had mentioned the fundamental reason and objective behind listening. I totally agreed that quick reply was not the objective of erecting our ears and attentively receiving the sound waves others uttered from the mouth. We need to do so because we want to understand what people are saying. Listening consumes more energy than speaking because it requires our brain to finish these tasks, receiving the sound, interpreting the words, and processing the information of the sentences, etc. Listen, and Listen well. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.guanghuiz.com/en/en/blog/2016/02/29/listen-and-listen-well/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.guanghuiz.com/en/en/blog/2016/02/29/listen-and-listen-well/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Interactive Data Visualization of Baseball Player Dataset</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;D3.js is a JavaScript library for manipulating documents based on data. D3 helps you bring data to life using HTML, SVG, and CSS. D3.js is an technology to create interactive data visualization. From my experience with d3js, it is really flexible to use. I created a visualization on a baseball player data sets and tried to explore whether the physical characteristics are related with their scores on the match field. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click to download &lt;a href=&quot;/en/data/baseball_data.csv&quot;&gt;baseball player dataset&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Click to view the &lt;a href=&quot;/en/data-science/data-visual-project-1.html&quot;&gt;data visualization project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.guanghuiz.com/en/en/data-science/2015/10/31/data-visualization-project-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.guanghuiz.com/en/en/data-science/2015/10/31/data-visualization-project-1/</guid>
        
        <category>data</category>
        
        <category>science,</category>
        
        <category>data</category>
        
        <category>viz</category>
        
        
        <category>data-science</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The year of 2014</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One thing I cannot deny definitely is that the year of 2014 is ending this soon. Being melancholy about how time flies is a cliche. Make a summary of what had happened in this year is more reasonable for a person like me who always can keep a degree of sanity. In order to avoid elaborating a boring list of events, I would try to add some excitements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early two months I had a great winter vacation back at home. Since I still have HWG702-Teaching Assistant Class unfinished and more unexpectedly fail to get make up classes from lecturers, spending Chinese New Year with my parents made me have to quit the class so as to avoid a failure mark on my grades report. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.guanghuiz.com/en/en/blog/2014/12/12/the-year-of-2014/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.guanghuiz.com/en/en/blog/2014/12/12/the-year-of-2014/</guid>
        
        <category>daily,</category>
        
        <category>2014</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I know the points of life</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I truely found how the points of life &lt;!--more--&gt;
are connected. I learned java, python, django, aws, android,
just by interest. Now I found all thesse could come together
to help me build an android app and its backend api.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.guanghuiz.com/en/en/blog/2014/11/27/i-truly-know-how-points-of-life-are-connected/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.guanghuiz.com/en/en/blog/2014/11/27/i-truly-know-how-points-of-life-are-connected/</guid>
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
